[Sharp Blade in the Snow]
[نصل حاد في الثلج]
[Episode 23]
[الحلقة 23]
Yun Zhan is the crown prince of Dongli.
يون زان هو ولي عهد دونغلي.
Lu Ran was originally his subordinate
كان لو ران في الأصل تابعًا له
and infiltrated Mocheng long ago.
وتسللوا إلى موتشينغ منذ زمن بعيد.
Under the banner of restoring their country,
تحت راية استعادة بلادهم،
he had lurked for so many years.
لقد ظل يتربص لسنوات عديدة.
Now, Lu Ran has betrayed Yun Zhan and colluded with Meng Wu.
الآن، خان لو ران يون تشان وتآمر مع مينغ وو.
They persuaded Feng Li to marry far away to Xiqi,
أقنعوا فنغ لي بالزواج من شي تشي البعيدة،
but they replaced her during the journey.
لكنهم استبدلوها أثناء الرحلة.
The real Feng Li
فينغ لي الحقيقية
has already fallen into their hands.
لقد وقعت بالفعل في أيديهم.
I'm afraid her life is in danger.
أخشى أن حياتها في خطر.
No wonder her eyes looked different.
لا عجب أن عينيها بدتا مختلفتين.
She didn't curse me
لم تلعنني
and didn't talk back.
ولم يردّ.
She isn't Feng Li at all.
إنها ليست فينغ لي على الإطلاق.
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
Meng Wu now has the Phoenix Seal
يمتلك مينغ وو الآن ختم العنقاء
and has Lu Ran's assistance.
ويحظى بمساعدة لو ران.
And I guess most of the court officials have already taken sides.
وأظن أن معظم مسؤولي المحكمة قد انحازوا بالفعل إلى أحد الطرفين.
With what power can I save her?
بأي قوة أستطيع إنقاذها؟
Me, a royal woman alone?
أنا، امرأة ملكية وحيدة؟
And half of the Tiger Tally?
ونصف حصيلة النمور؟
Feng Ling'er,
فنغ لينغ إير،
calm down and think carefully.
اهدأ وفكر جيداً.
There must be a way
لا بد من وجود حل
to save Feng Li.
لإنقاذ فنغ لي.
I'm alone and weak,
أنا وحيد وضعيف،
but Xin Yao is the young master of Xiqi
لكن شين ياو هو السيد الشاب لشي تشي
and once formed an alliance with Feng Li.
وشكّل ذات مرة تحالفاً مع فنغ لي.
Perhaps
ربما
he is the only help
هو المعين الوحيد
I can find right now.
يمكنني إيجادها الآن.
Feng Li hasn't been eating or sleeping well lately.
لم يكن فينغ لي يأكل أو ينام جيداً في الآونة الأخيرة.
She needs some medicinal tonic to regulate her body.
إنها بحاجة إلى بعض الأدوية المقوية لتنظيم وظائف جسمها.
It's poisoned.
إنه مسموم.
This is bad.
هذا سيء.
Princess Royal actually made a move against Xin Yao.
قامت الأميرة الملكية بالفعل بخطوة ضد شين ياو.
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
A-Aunt.
العمة.
Ling'er,
لينغ،
strolling in the garden at this hour,
التجول في الحديقة في هذا الوقت،
aren't you afraid of seeing something
ألا تخاف من رؤية شيء ما؟
you shouldn't?
ألا يجب عليك ذلك؟
Aunt,
عمة،
I...
أنا...
I didn't see anything.
لم أرَ شيئاً.
Really.
حقًا.
I just came out for some fresh air.
خرجتُ لأستنشق بعض الهواء النقي.
I had no idea... I'd bump into someone.
لم أكن أتوقع... أن أصطدم بشخص ما.
Ling'er,
لينغ،
don't be afraid.
لا تخف.
I'm just teasing you.
أنا فقط أمازحك.
Even if you saw something, it's fine.
حتى لو رأيت شيئًا ما، فلا بأس.
Haven't you always felt
ألم تشعر دائمًا
Feng Li is so high and mighty,
فنغ لي متغطرس ومتعجرف للغاية،
looking down on you?
ينظر إليك باستعلاء؟
I know you feel wronged.
أعلم أنك تشعر بالظلم.
Your bloodline
نسبك
is just as noble as hers.
هي نبيلة مثلها تماماً.
It's time
حان الوقت
for someone to fight for the justice you deserve.
أن تجد من يناضل من أجل العدالة التي تستحقها.
Aunt,
عمة،
I don't understand what you're talking about.
لا أفهم ما تتحدث عنه.
On the wedding day,
في يوم الزفاف،
I will make sure you obtain
سأحرص على حصولك على
the honor you deserve
التكريم الذي تستحقه
and become the true Princess Ling.
وتصبح الأميرة لينغ الحقيقية.
Thank you, Aunt.
شكراً لكِ يا عمتي.
I won't let you down.
لن أخذلكم.
What I like most about you
أكثر ما يعجبني فيك
is that you are sensible.
هذا يعني أنك شخص عاقل.
[Liuyun Palace]
[قصر ليويون]
Lu Ran.
لو ران.
Remove his mask.
انزع قناعه.
He has quite a handsome face.
لديه وجه وسيم للغاية.
Check again
تحقق مرة أخرى
if there's anything that can prove his identity.
إذا كان هناك أي شيء يمكن أن يثبت هويته.
Yes.
نعم.
[Token]
[رمز مميز]
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
this token...
هذا الرمز...
[Token]
[رمز مميز]
is the credential of Xiqi's young master.
هذه هي وثيقة اعتماد سيد شي تشي الشاب.
There is no second one like it.
لا يوجد مثيل له.
I'm 100% sure.
أنا متأكد بنسبة 100%.
So he truly is the young master of Xiqi.
إذن فهو حقاً السيد الشاب لفن شي تشي.
I just searched the entire body
لقد فتشت الجثة بأكملها
and found something suspicious.
ووجدوا شيئاً مثيراً للريبة.
This young master of Xiqi...
هذا الشاب الماهر في فن شي تشي...
is a woman.
هي امرأة.
This person...
هذا الشخص...
is actually a woman.
هي في الواقع امرأة.
No wonder the young master of Xiqi
لا عجب أن السيد الشاب لـ Xiqi
has worn a mask since childhood.
كان يرتدي قناعاً منذ طفولته.
So that's why.
لهذا السبب.
Xiqi's young master is a woman.
سيد شي تشي الشاب امرأة.
The young master of a state is actually a woman disguised as a man,
إن الحاكم الشاب للدولة هو في الحقيقة امرأة متنكرة في زي رجل.
hiding in the court.
الاختباء في المحكمة.
If this is revealed to the world,
إذا انكشف هذا للعالم،
Xiqi will surely fall into chaos.
سيقع شي تشي بالتأكيد في حالة من الفوضى.
Once Xiqi is in chaos,
بمجرد أن تسود الفوضى في شي تشي،
it will be the perfect time for Mocheng to annex it.
سيكون هذا هو الوقت المثالي لموتشنغ لضمها.
A heaven-sent opportunity.
فرصة منحة من السماء.
Aunt, clearly you're blessed by Heaven.
يا عمتي، من الواضح أنكِ مباركة من السماء.
Xiqi
شيتشي
will be the next Dongli.
سيكون هو دونغلي القادم.
Ling'er,
لينغ،
as long as you obey me,
طالما أنك تطيعني،
a share of this world
حصة من هذا العالم
will surely be yours.
سيكون لك بالتأكيد.
As for this person,
أما بالنسبة لهذا الشخص،
before the wedding ceremony,
قبل حفل الزفاف،
let her continue her act.
دعها تُكمل تمثيلها.
Once the ceremony is over,
بمجرد انتهاء الحفل،
after we obtain the Phoenix Incense and the puppet wood,
بعد أن نحصل على بخور العنقاء وخشب الدمى،
we can expose her identity.
يمكننا كشف هويتها.
Aunt,
عمة،
she once spoke disrespectfully to me.
لقد تحدثت معي ذات مرة بأسلوب غير لائق.
I've held a grudge ever since.
لقد حملت ضغينة منذ ذلك الحين.
Why don't you...
لماذا لا تفعل ذلك...
leave her to me?
هل تتركها لي؟
I'll ensure she won't cause any trouble.
سأضمن أنها لن تسبب أي مشاكل.
Okay, Ling'er.
حسناً، انتظر قليلاً.
Since that's what you want,
بما أن هذا ما تريده،
I feel quite reassured.
أشعر بالاطمئنان التام.
But you must remember:
لكن يجب أن تتذكر:
don't harm her life.
لا تؤذي حياتها.
Don't ruin
لا تفسد
my perfect plan.
خطتي المثالية.
I understand.
أفهم.
I won't disappoint you.
لن أخيب ظنك.
Young Master of Xiqi, you're finally awake.
سيد شي تشي الشاب، لقد استيقظت أخيرًا.
This appearance of yours
هذا المظهر الذي تظهره
is truly a rare sight.
إنه مشهد نادر حقاً.
You removed my mask?
هل نزعت قناعي؟
Has the smoke addled your brain?
هل أثر الدخان على عقلك؟
You were taken away by Meng Wu and Lu Ran.
تم أخذك بعيدًا بواسطة مينغ وو ولو ران.
They discovered your identity.
لقد اكتشفوا هويتك.
Out of kindness,
من باب اللطف،
I asked them for you.
سألتهم نيابة عنك.
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك،
you would've been tortured to death by Lu Ran by now.
لو كنت قد تعرضت للتعذيب حتى الموت على يد لو ران الآن.
What... is this place?
ما هذا المكان؟
My territory, of course.
منطقتي، بالطبع.
The Fengling Hall.
قاعة فينغلينغ.
Of course,
بالطبع،
you're now
أنت الآن
in my hands.
بين يدي.
Xin...
اطلب...
Yao?
لهم؟
I am not Xin Yao.
أنا لست شين ياو.
My name is Xin Miao.
اسمي شين مياو.
I apologize for offending you before,
أعتذر إن كنت قد أسأت إليك سابقاً،
especially in the palace.
وخاصة في القصر.
For my rudeness,
بسبب وقاحتي،
I apologize. I was reckless.
أعتذر. لقد كنت متهوراً.
I'm not that petty.
أنا لستُ بتلك التفاهة.
But if you truly feel
لكن إذا كنت تشعر حقًا
guilty toward me,
أشعر بالذنب تجاهي،
after listening to what I have to say,
بعد الاستماع إلى ما سأقوله،
just cooperate obediently.
تعاونوا بطاعة.
Last night, I went to the prison
ذهبت إلى السجن الليلة الماضية
and saw Yun Zhan.
ورأى يون زان.
How is he?
كيف حاله؟
Is he still alive?
هل ما زال على قيد الحياة؟
We agreed before entering the palace
اتفقنا قبل دخول القصر
that he would enter as a criminal slave
أنه سيدخل كعبد مجرم
and then find a way to escape
ثم ابحث عن طريقة للهروب
to reunite with us.
لكي نلتقي مجدداً.
But now there hasn't been any news.
لكن لم ترد أي أخبار الآن.
He was tricked by Lu Ran.
لقد خدعه لو ران.
Originally, they were on the same side,
في الأصل، كانوا في نفس الجانب،
but Lu Ran betrayed him long ago.
لكن لو ران خانته منذ زمن بعيد.
Now he's colluded with Meng Wu,
والآن تواطأ مع مينغ وو،
planning to take Feng Li's life
يخططون لقتل فنغ لي
and seize power in the Wutong Palace.
والاستيلاء على السلطة في قصر ووتونغ.
Yun Zhan told me to come to you.
قال لي يون زان أن آتي إليك.
He said only you can save Feng Li now.
قال: أنت وحدك من يستطيع إنقاذ فينغ لي الآن.
The real Feng Li...
فينغ لي الحقيقية...
was already replaced by Lu Ran
تم استبدالها بالفعل بلو ران
during your journey back to Mocheng.
أثناء رحلة عودتك إلى موتشنغ.
The one waiting
الشخص المنتظر
for your wedding in the palace now
لحفل زفافك في القصر الآن
is an impostor.
إنه دجال.
No wonder.
لا عجب في ذلك.
I always felt something was off.
لطالما شعرت أن هناك شيئاً ما ليس على ما يرام.
Where is Feng Li now?
أين فنغ لي الآن؟
Is she still alive?
هل ما زالت على قيد الحياة؟
I think she's still alive,
أعتقد أنها لا تزال على قيد الحياة.
but I'm afraid she won't hold on much longer.
لكنني أخشى أنها لن تصمد لفترة أطول.
Lu Ran and Meng Wu will make their move sooner or later.
سيقوم لو ران ومينغ وو بخطوتهما عاجلاً أم آجلاً.
Or perhaps...
أو ربما...
they'll simply end everything
سوف ينهون كل شيء ببساطة
on the wedding day.
في يوم الزفاف.
If you truly want to save her,
إذا كنت تريد حقًا إنقاذها،
do as I say.
افعل ما أقوله.
Go to the Apricot Blossom Study in the west of the city,
اذهب إلى مركز دراسة زهر المشمش في غرب المدينة،
and embed a stone in a crack in the wall.
وغرس حجر في شق في الجدار.
If my brother sees it,
إذا رآه أخي،
he'll know I'm sending a message.
سيعرف أنني أرسل رسالة.
Your brother?
أخوك؟
The real Xin Yao?
هل هذا هو شين ياو الحقيقي؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Before coming to Mocheng,
قبل القدوم إلى موتشنغ،
we agreed
اتفقنا
I would appear openly in male disguise,
سأظهر علنًا متنكرًا بزي رجل،
while he'd remain hidden.
بينما سيبقى مختبئاً.
If danger arises, he would save us.
إذا ما نشأ خطر، فسوف ينقذنا.
He's a skilled strategist.
إنه خبير استراتيجي ماهر.
We might
ربما
be able to solve this problem.
أن يكون قادراً على حل هذه المشكلة.
Princess Ling,
الأميرة لينغ،
now we can only rely on you.
الآن لا يمكننا الاعتماد إلا عليك.
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحية طيبة، صاحب السمو.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Li's big day is approaching.
يوم لي الكبير يقترب.
What a pity.
يا للأسف.
Sister,
أخت،
you won't be able to see it.
لن تتمكن من رؤيته.
[In Memory of The Late Queen of Mocheng]
[في ذكرى ملكة موتشنغ الراحلة]
Sister,
أخت،
look.
ينظر.
The last time the palace was this lively
آخر مرة كان فيها القصر بهذه الحيوية
was during your wedding.
كان ذلك خلال حفل زفافك.
Now,
الآن،
it is finally awash in red again.
لقد غمرها اللون الأحمر من جديد.
You were the legitimate daughter of the Feng family.
كنتِ الابنة الشرعية لعائلة فينغ.
You were the queen revered by all.
كنتِ الملكة التي يحترمها الجميع.
While I was
بينما كنت
merely a shadow.
مجرد ظل.
All those years,
كل تلك السنوات،
I learned to walk like you
لقد تعلمت المشي مثلك
and imitated your way of speaking.
وقلّد طريقة كلامك.
Every single detail about you—
كل تفاصيلك؟
no one knows better than I do.
لا أحد يعرف أفضل مني.
When you smiled,
عندما ابتسمت،
the entire palace rejoiced.
ابتهج القصر بأكمله.
But when I shed tears,
لكن عندما ذرفت الدموع،
no one even bothered to ask.
لم يكلف أحد نفسه عناء السؤال.
Soon,
قريباً،
someone
شخص ما
will put on the wedding dress that should have belonged
سأرتدي فستان الزفاف الذي كان من المفترض أن يكون لي.
to your daughter.
إلى ابنتك.
She will take Feng Li's throne,
ستتولى عرش فنغ لي،
her husband,
زوجها،
and everything else.
وكل شيء آخر.
Just like me back then,
تمامًا مثلي في ذلك الوقت،
she'll become
ستصبح
a shadow that no one...
ظلٌّ لم يره أحد...
cares about.
يهتم بـ.
Sister,
أخت،
this is my revenge against you.
هذا انتقامي منك.
This time,
هذه المرة،
I won't lose again.
لن أخسر مرة أخرى.